SATHIYA G

Technical Writer

An IT professional with 6+ years of experience in academic&Technical writing, SEO, and digital marketing. To secure a position in the field of technical communication where I can maximize my technical skills, quality assurance, program development, and training experience.



gsathyaguna@gmail.com 🔀

9080275554

Bangalore, India Q

linkedin.com/in/sathya-guna-5748191bb in

WORK EXPERIENCE

Academic Writer Venper Academy

08/2019 - 11/2020 NEET/JEE Coaching Institute Chennai

Roles and Responsibilities

- Involved in the creation and revision of quality academic content for competitive exams aspirants (JEE, NEET, JAM). Composed creative and innovative academic content for organizational websites.
- Carried out extensive online research and reference several books of leading authors to develop the latest academic content including test papers & assignments.
- Implemented and developed the given projects with the use of MSTP, DDLC and Agile scrum methodology.
- Assisted and managed the marketing team, allocated data for the team member, and get follow-ups with them, maintained updated tracker sheets, targets, and other reports.

Academic Content Writer

Sree Sastha Institute of Engineering and Technology

07/2018 - 07/2019 Group of educational institution Chennai

Roles and Responsibilities

- Created content for the website with the use of SEO practices to generate traffic for the site.
- Produced various content for email, social media posts, blogs.
 Storyboard, Creative Posts on Facebook/ Linkedin.
- Handled and Coordinated for the NACC work.

Administrative CoordinatorSri Venkateswara College of Engineering and Technology

03/2016 - 07/2018 Engineering college Chennai

Roles and Responsibilities

- Web portal maintenance for DOTE work. Students and, Staff data managed using a database management system.
- Monitor inventory of office supplies and the purchasing of new materials with attention to budgetary constraints.
- Created Content for the website.

Search Engine Optimization Analyst The Spider India

12/2010 - 04/2012

Chennai

website and mobile application development

Roles and Responsibilities

- Performed keyword research in coordination with client business objectives to optimize existing content and uncover new opportunities.
- Keep pace with SEO, search engine, social media, and internet marketing, and industry trends and developments.
- Experience with Website analysis using a variety of analytics tools including Google Analytics as well as internal reporting tool.

SKILLS



EDUCATION

MCA-Indira Institute Of Computer Application (2007 - /2010)

Percentage- Distinction with 76.2%

BSc(Computer Science)-STET Women's College (2004 - /2010)

Percentage - First class with 65.7%

HSC- State Board Tamilnadu (2003 - 2004) Percentage- 58.8%

SSLC- State Board Tamilnadu (2001 - 2002) Percentage- 77.4%

CERTIFICATES

Technical Communication Mentoring Program (09/2020 - 12/2020) ASTEP

Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate (12/2020)

Ceritiprof Professional Knowledge

SQL/PLSQL Certification Course (03/2018 - 06/2018)

Greens Technology, Chennai.

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Tamil

Full Professional Proficiency